hi everybody welcome back to the channel
I'm Nick and today we're gonna do sorbet
and I've never had sorbet before
so if you watch this channel you know I
love chocolate ice cream I don't really
make fruit based ice creams that often
we did an orange one recently we've done
a few banana ones but now we're gonna do
sorbet it's my first time I did seek
some advice from a woman called Chiara
who I've mentioned a few times actually
in the past I'll put a link to her
website below she offers courses on how
to do ice cream so if you want to
venture down that path then go for it
we're going to do raspberry sorbet it's
actually quite easy to do and we're
going to stabilize it with pectin so
let's get on and show you how we did it
so these are the ingredients you're
going to need you're going to need your
sugar your dextrose and your dried
pectin here and obviously your
raspberries you needed a blender for
this one too and then just straight
water so here we're going to put our
water in and you can see what happens
here people ask me what happens if you
don't put stabilizers in Sugar this is
pectin it acts the same as a stabilizer
you put it in without the sugar and you
are going to fight this until you're
blue in the face it will not dissolve
properly so what we did started again we
took the water off added new ones
cleaned the pan and then we added the
pectin in with the sugar here as you can
see and then put that little lot into
the water and the dextrose and bring
that up to a nice boil just to make sure
that the pectin is going to work
properly and it's completely dissolved
in the water
it will thicken ever so slightly at that
stage take it off the heat and let it
cool down for about 20 to 30 minutes
once it's cooled down you're going to
take your blender and your raspberries
and put them all in along with your
syrup mix make sure you turn your
blender on unlike me and then go to town
absolutely pulverize it for a good
minute or so once you've done that
strain it through a fine mesh sieve and
then put that mix in the fridge for
three to four hours to chill down once
it's completely chilled you're going to
pop it in your ice cream machine as you
would do normally again give it a nice
little stir just to make sure before you
do and then what you'll see happen is it
will lighten in color during the
churning process after about 15 to 20
minutes depending on your machine at
that stage take it out tub it up and pop
it in the freezer
let's
get some of this raspberry red sorbet
dished up
[Music]
there we go
sorbet I don't know why I don't know
sorbets who knows I mean I've had
some pretty crap ice creams maybe it was
a sorbet when I was a kid or younger and
I don't remember that kind of put me off
but historically sorbets are really
really icy and that's something that I
wanted to seek advice on before I
actually started this is because they
don't have to be and just scooping this
one alone I mean if you could smell the
raspberry smell coming off of it it's
incredible it's really strong and that's
because we didn't cook The Raspberries
off that left that pure unadulterated
raspberry flavor and smell to go into
this base it's scooped like ice cream it
looks really creamy it's melting kind of
like ice cream too so let's just try
some
foreign
[Music]
that's quite Pleasant
it's a really nice strong raspberry
flavor like I said the smell the taste
is very natural
the pectin is what is the key here
you've raspberry is a fruit that doesn't
have a lot of pectin in it pectin in it
so you're not gonna get that thickened
kind of Base when you make it so adding
that pectin in allows the water or the
free water to be stabilized into a more
viscous emulsion
and then when you blend it all together
it churns a bit more like ice cream
rather than something like granita which
is really just ice crystals scraped up
and served which is horrible I don't I
just don't like it but this is It's
silky smooth on the tongue it's a really
strong pungent flavor
this is a winner I think if you served a
like a nice quinnelle if you can do that
I can't a nice little serving of this
with a deep rich chocolate ice cream I
think that's a combo to die for I'm sure
so
my first sorbet you've seen it here on
YouTube first we'll likely do some more
in the future as well so if you want to
see more of this kind of thing don't
forget to like And subscribe and we'll
see you next week
[Music]